<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ocean | Symbiosis | Climate Justice  on Natalia Galud Erazo</title>
    <link>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ocean | Symbiosis | Climate Justice  on Natalia Galud Erazo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mangrove PhD research</title>
      <link>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/projects/mangrove-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/projects/mangrove-6/</guid>
      <description>Mangroves are ecologically and globally important, and communities around the world depend on mangroves for coastal protection, carbon sequestration, and food resources associated to mangrove-dependent fisheries. Mangrove forests support a high diversity of microorganisms present in the soil, the water column, and most notably as thick biofilms on aerial and belowground roots.
Microbes perform many beneficial functions for their mangrove hosts such as helping to acquire nutrients, resist diseases and adapt to salinity stress, but the majority of microbes are unknown and uncharacterized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living in symbiosis | Afro-Ecuadorian communities, mangrove forests and cockles</title>
      <link>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/projects/guardinas-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/projects/guardinas-7/</guid>
      <description>Local ecological knowledge (LEK) systems and the connection of people to mangroves have been overlooked in marine science research, conservation, and policy. Dismissal of LEK has resulted in harmful global impacts to local communities and marine life. Dominant forms of knowledge like science are western based frameworks that tend to prioritize deterministic quantitative, large scale knowledge that in some instances it can operate under extractive ways, in contrast LEK is qualitative oral record that encompasses culture and local understanding and is applied to daily living and traditional subsistence practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean Cruise at RV Sally Ride</title>
      <link>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/projects/cruise-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/projects/cruise-5/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity to co-lead my first ocean cruise in 2023. This project emerged as a collaboration with Dr. Tricia Light. We worked together and wrote a proposal to do science on the Scripps research vessel (RV) Sally Ride. We also proposed and run a grad student seminar with the help of mentors and other researchers.
The Ocean cruise: The cruise offered an educational experience to students who might not have otherwise had the opportunity to go to sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Career Ocean Professionals</title>
      <link>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/projects/ecop-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/projects/ecop-4/</guid>
      <description>ECOPs and ocean solutions: Solutions to complex and unprecedented global challenges are urgently needed. Overcoming these challenges requires input and innovative solutions from all experts, including Early Career Ocean Professionals (ECOPs). To achieve diverse inclusion from ECOPs, fundamental changes must occur at all levels—from individuals to organizations. Drawing on insights from across the globe, we propose 5 actionable pillars that support the engagement of ECOPs in co-design processes that address ocean sustainability:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marine science and microbial ecology</title>
      <link>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/projects/other-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/projects/other-3/</guid>
      <description>Island-ocean connections:
This project examines the importance of island-ocean linkages and how disturbances like invasive species could have impacts not only in the terrestrial ecosystems but also in adjacent marine ecosystems. The work here examines key characteristics that strength land-sea linkage: precipitation, vegetation, soil hydrology, oceanographic productivity and wave energy.
Publication: Sandin, S. A., Becker, P. A., Becker, C., Brown, K., Erazo, N. G., Figuerola, C., &amp;hellip; Zgliczynski, B. J. (2022).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coastal seasonal microbiome and harmful algal blooms</title>
      <link>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/projects/pier-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/projects/pier-2/</guid>
      <description>View from the sampling station at the Scripps Pier.
Seasonal changes are crucial in marine microbiomes and can impact nutrient availability, light availability, dissolved oxygen levels, and community interactions. Complex biological and physical processes contribute to microbial community turn over. Understanding what factors contribute to shifts in microbial community structure and what organisms correlate with changes in the products of photosynthesis can improve our understanding of nearshore microbial ecosystem functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seagrass microbiome</title>
      <link>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/projects/seagrass-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/projects/seagrass-1/</guid>
      <description>Seagrass in San Diego Bay forms beds and meadows that provide food and refugee for fish, and they serve as natural defense against pollution. In this study we examined the impact of Zostera species (a type of seagrass) on bacteria and archaea community structure.
Publications:
Webb, S. J., Rabsatt, T., Erazo, N., &amp;amp; Bowman, J. S. (2019). Impacts of Zostera eelgrasses on microbial community structure in San Diego coastal waters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Natalia (she/her), I&amp;rsquo;m from Ecuador and I grew up in ancestral homelands of Kitu Kara territory.
I&amp;rsquo;m PhD candidate at Scripps Institution of Oceanography and member of the Bowman Lab (https://www.polarmicrobes.org/). My research examines the role of marine microbial communities in ecosystem function and responses to pollution, with particular focus on understanding the drivers of symbiosis and how microbiomes provide resilience to anthropogenic stress. My work involves understanding drivers of microbial community structure, diversity, function, and implications to biogeochemistry in coastal ecosystems; examining mangrove-microbe interactions and responses to salinity and pathogenic stress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://galud27.github.io/Natalia_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for your interest in my work! I&amp;rsquo;m always looking to collaborate on ocean-people relations, microbiomes, symbiosis; and developing frameworks and ways of doing that involve recognizing different forms of knowledge, listening and building trust, ocean ethics and decolonize access to do science differently and building networks rooted on solidarity and resistance. Feel free to send me an email (nerazo@ucsd.edu).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
